{"Topic": "Legal G.K.", "Subject": "General Knowledge", "Data": [{"Question": "Who of the following is the Chancellor of the NALSAR University of Law located in Hyderabad?", "op1": "Governor of A.P.", "op2": "The Union Law Minister", "op3": "Chief Justice of A.P. High Court", "op4": "Solicitor General of India", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "Who is the Legal Advisor to the Government of a State in India?", "op1": "The Solicitor General", "op2": "The State Chief Legal Officer", "op3": "The High Court", "op4": "The Advocate General"}, {"Question": "With which of the following issues did D.K. Basu v. State of West Bengal deal with?", "op1": "Safeguards against sexual exploitation", "op2": "Safeguards for arrested persons", "op3": "Safeguards for children", "op4": "Safeguards for unorganized workers", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "The age of retirement of a Judge of a High Court in India is", "op1": "58 years", "op2": "60 years", "op3": "62 years", "op4": "65 years", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "In law, the term 'neighbour' means", "op1": "People who might be affected by your actions", "op2": "People who stay in your locality", "op3": "People who live adjoining to your residence", "op4": "The word has not been given any particular definition", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "In which of the following cases did the Supreme Court direct the compulsory registration of all marriages in India?", "op1": "Danial Latifi vs Union of India", "op2": "Ashok Kumar vs Union of India", "op3": "Seema vs Ashwini Kumar", "op4": "Sharda vs Dharampal", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Which of the following principles is applicable for the purpose of reducing multiplicity of proceedings?", "op1": "Res getae", "op2": "Res interregnum", "op3": "Res judicata", "op4": "Res ispa loquitor", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Which of the following best describes the legal phrase amicus curiae?", "op1": "let the buyer beware", "op2": "friend of the court", "op3": "at one's own risk", "op4": "on what authority"}, {"Question": "In which of the following cases did the Supreme Court for the first time lay down that Fundamental Rights have primacy over the Directive Principles of State Policy?", "op1": "Keshavananda Bharati vs State of Punjab", "op2": "A.K. Roy vs Union of India", "op3": "ADM Jabalpur vs Shiv Kant Shukla", "op4": "Minerva Mills vs Union of India", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Which of the following writs can be used against a person believed to be holding a public office he is not entitled to hold?", "op1": "Mandamus", "op2": "Quo Warranto", "op3": "Habaes Corpus", "op4": "Certiorari", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "Which of the following is entrusted with a statutory duty of laying down the standards of professional conduct and etiquette for advocates in India?", "op1": "Supreme Court of India", "op2": "Bar Association of India", "op3": "Bar Council of India", "op4": "Delhi Bar Council", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "A person has designed a new type of scissors for cutting of clothes. Under which act can he seek protection of his invention?", "op1": "The Patents Act", "op2": "The Copyrights Act", "op3": "Consumer Protection Act", "op4": "Arms Control Act", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Which of the following laws deal with intellectual property protection for horticultural products?", "op1": "Protection of Plant Varieties and Farmers Rights Act", "op2": "Horticultural Products (Protection of Intellectual Property) Act", "op3": "Agricultural Patents Act", "op4": "Protection to Biological Innovations Act", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Match the names of writs in List I with their meanings in List II.", "op1": "1 - B; 2 - D; 3 - A; 4 - C", "op2": "1 - B; 2 - A; 3 - D; 4 - C", "op3": "1 - C; 2 - D; 3 - A; 4 - B", "op4": "1 - C; 2 - A; 3 - D; 4 - B", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Who among the following was the first person to be directly appointed as the Judge of Supreme Court?", "op1": "N Santosh Hegde", "op2": "Ghulam E Vanhavati", "op3": "Kuldeep Singh", "op4": "V.R. Krishna Iyer", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "What is the maximum time limit for filing of a complaint before the consumer disputes redressal forum from the date when the cause of action arises?", "op1": "one year", "op2": "two years", "op3": "three years", "op4": "four years", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Under which law a minor is incapable of entering into contract?", "op1": "Indian Contract Act, 1872", "op2": "Majority Act, 1875", "op3": "Guardians and Wards Act, 1890", "op4": "Contract Labour ((Regulation and Abolition) Act, 1970", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Which of the following writs is said to be a guarantor of personal freedom?", "op1": "Mandamus", "op2": "Quo Warranto", "op3": "Habaes Corpus", "op4": "Certiorari", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "The power to issue writs has been envisaged under the provisions of which of the following fundamental rights?", "op1": "Right to Equality", "op2": "Right to Freedom", "op3": "Right to Constitutional Remedies", "op4": "Right against Exploitation"}, {"Question": "Rule of Law means -", "op1": "all persons are equal in the eyes of law", "op2": "treating all unequally as equals", "op3": "working according to law", "op4": "distributing state largesse to everyone in equal proportion", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Which of the following writs can be issued to force a public authority to perform a public or statutory duty.?", "op1": "Mandamus", "op2": "Habeas Corpus", "op3": "Certiorari", "op4": "Quo Warranto", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "In which landmark judgment did the Supreme Court of India lay down guidelines against sexual harassment of women at workplace?", "op1": "Nilabati Behera vs. State of Orissa", "op2": "Vishakha vs. State of Rajasthan", "op3": "Maneka Gandhi vs. Union of India.", "op4": "Hussainara Khatoon vs. State of Bihar", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "The marriage of a 15 year old girl with a 45 year old man is -", "op1": "valid", "op2": "invalid", "op3": "voidable at the option of the girl", "op4": "voidable at the will of the man", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "What does the legal term Caveat Emptor refer to?", "op1": "Let the buyer beware", "op2": "According to value", "op3": "An unwelcome person", "op4": "Beyond the powers"}, {"Question": "Who was the first woman judge to be appointed to the Supreme Court of India?", "op1": "Justice Smt Gyan Sudha Mishra", "op2": "Justice Smt M. Fathima Beevi", "op3": "Justice Smt Leila Seth", "op4": "Justice Smt Ranjana Desai", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Who was the first woman judge to be appointed Chief Justice of a High Court?", "op1": "Justice Smt Gyan Sudha Mishra", "op2": "Justice Smt M. Fathima Beevi", "op3": "Justice Smt Leila Seth", "op4": "Justice Smt Ranjana Desai", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "In which of the following cases did the Supreme Court allow Passive Euthanasia under exceptional circumstances?", "op1": "Gian Kaur vs. State of Punjab", "op2": "Aruna Shanbaug vs. Union of India", "op3": "Sharda vs. Union of India", "op4": "Seema vs. Ashwini Kumar", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "What is the total number of High Courts in India?", "op1": "21", "op2": "22", "op3": "24", "op4": "19"}, {"Question": "Andaman and Nicobar islands come under the jurisdiction of which of the following High Courts?", "op1": "Calcutta High Court", "op2": "Madras High Court", "op3": "Port Blair High Court", "op4": "Delhi High Court", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Sharda Act deals with", "op1": "Widow Remarriage", "op2": "Child Marriage", "op3": "Inter-caste Marriage", "op4": "Polygamy", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Who of the following is credited with drafting the Indian Penal Code, 1860?", "op1": "Sir James Stephen", "op2": "Charles Wood", "op3": "John Morley", "op4": "Lord Macaulay", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "In which one of the following judgments of the Constitutional Bench of the Supreme Court of India, the 'rarest of rare' principle in the award of death penalty was first laid down?", "op1": "Bachan Singh v. State of Punjab (1980)", "op2": "Gopalanachari v. State of Kerala (1980)", "op3": "Dr. Upendra Baxi v. State of UP (1983)", "op4": "Tukaram v. State of Maharashtra (1979)", "Answer": 2}]}